<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Academic</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIStsp: a new &#34;R&#34; package for MODIS Land Products preprocessing</title>
      <link>/post/modistsp-a-new-r-package-for-modis-land-products-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modistsp-a-new-r-package-for-modis-land-products-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we are introducing MODIStsp a new &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; package allowing to automatize the creation of time series of rasters derived from Land Products data derived from MODIS satellite data (; www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0098300416303107).
Development of MODIStsp started from modifications of the ModisDownload &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; script by Thomas Hengl (spatial-analyst.net/wiki/index.php?title=Download_and_resampling_of_MODIS_images), and successive adaptations by Babak Naimi (r-gis.net/?q=ModisDownload). Their functionalities were gradually incremented with the aim of:
 Developing a standalone application allowing to perform several preprocessing steps (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to this Blog</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hi all,
I&amp;rsquo;ll use this blog to share posts mostly related to tips and tricks about Spatial Processing and satellite image analysis in &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo;, as well as to share interesting resources concerning &amp;ldquo;R&amp;rdquo; programming in general.
HTH,
Lorenzo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>